<resources>
    <string name="app_name" translatable="false">Baku</string>

    <string name="category_historical_landmarks">Historical Landmarks</string>

    <string name="title1_HL">Old City (Icherisheher)</string>
    <string name="subtitle1_HL">Downtown Baku</string>
    <string name="short_description1_HL">The historic heart of Baku, surrounded by well-preserved 12th-century fortress walls.</string>
    <string name="full_description1_HL">
        Step back in time inside Baku\'s oldest residential quarter.
        Known as Icherisheher, this maze of narrow alleys, ancient mosques, and caravanserais houses the famous Maiden Tower and the Palace of the Shirvanshahs.
        It’s a living open-air museum and a UNESCO World Heritage site.
    </string>

    <string name="title2_HL">Heydar Aliyev Center</string>
    <string name="subtitle2_HL">Narimanov District</string>
    <string name="short_description2_HL">An architectural masterpiece designed by Zaha Hadid, famous for its flowing, curved lines.</string>
    <string name="full_description2_HL">
        This world-renowned cultural center challenges traditional architecture with its fluid, continuous shape that emerges from the landscape.
        It hosts various exhibition spaces, a museum, and a concert hall, representing the modern, futuristic face of Baku.
    </string>

    <string name="title3_HL"> Flame Towers &amp; Highland Park</string>
    <string name="subtitle3_HL">Parliamentary Avenue</string>
    <string name="short_description3_HL">A trio of flame-shaped skyscrapers offering the best panoramic views of Baku.</string>
    <string name="full_description3_HL">
        Towering over the Baku bay, these three iconic skyscrapers symbolize the city\'s history of fire worship and its modern
        energy wealth. Accessible by a funicular, the adjacent Highland Park (Dagustu Park) provides a breathtaking 360-degree
        view of the entire city and the Caspian Sea, especially beautiful at night when the towers light up like real fire.
    </string>

    <string name="title4_HL">Ateshgah (Fire Temple)</string>
    <string name="subtitle4_HL">Surakhany Suburb</string>
    <string name="short_description4_HL">An ancient castle-like religious temple built over natural gas vents.</string>
    <string name="full_description4_HL">
        Located on the Absheron Peninsula, this pentagonal complex was used as a place of worship by Zoroastrian,
        Hindu, and Sikh pilgrims over the centuries. The central altar sits on a natural pocket of natural gas that
        used to burn eternally, creating a mystical and historical atmosphere outside the city center.
    </string>



    <string name="category_walks_and_recreation">Walks &amp; Recreation</string>

    <string name="title1_WandR">Baku Boulevard</string>
    <string name="subtitle1_WandR">Caspian Sea Coastline</string>
    <string name="short_description1_WandR">A century-old promenade stretching along the Caspian Sea, perfect for long walks.</string>
    <string name="full_description1_WandR">
        Established in 1909, this massive seaside park runs parallel to Baku\'s seafront. It features lush green lanes,
        open-air cafés, bike rentals, and historical amusement rides.It is the social heart of the city where locals and
        tourists gather to catch the refreshing sea breeze.
    </string>

    <string name="title2_WandR">Nizami Street (Torgovaya)</string>
    <string name="subtitle2_WandR">Downtown Baku</string>
    <string name="short_description2_WandR">A vibrant, fully pedestrianized street famous for its stunning architecture and shopping.</string>
    <string name="full_description2_WandR">
        Commonly known as Torgovaya, this central pedestrian avenue is lined with elegant late-19th-century buildings featuring European
        architectural styles. The street comes alive in the evening with brilliant overhead lighting installations, street musicians,
        local boutiques, and dozens of cozy restaurants.
    </string>

    <string name="title3_WandR">Little Venice</string>
    <string name="subtitle3_WandR">Baku Boulevard</string>
    <string name="short_description3_WandR">A picturesque system of clean water canals and stone bridges inside the Boulevard.</string>
    <string name="full_description3_WandR">
        Built in the 1960s, this charming park recreates a mini Venetian experience right by the Caspian Sea.
        Visitors can ride authentic gondolas through shallow, bright-blue water channels, passing by small green islands,
        marble bridges, and outdoor restaurants.
    </string>

    <string name="title4_WandR">Dede Gorgud Park</string>
    <string name="subtitle4_WandR">Narimanov District</string>
    <string name="short_description4_WandR">A modern, peaceful park featuring a large artificial lake and green lawns.</string>
    <string name="full_description4_WandR">
        This is one of the newer and largest recreational parks in the city center. It offers a calm escape from the urban rush,
        featuring a beautiful central lake where you can rent paddle boats, well-maintained wooden pathways, and plenty of space
        for picnics under shady trees.
    </string>



    <string name="category_food">Taste of Baku</string>

    <string name="title1_F">Traditional Tea Houses (Chaykhana)</string>
    <string name="subtitle1_F">Old City (Icherisheher)</string>
    <string name="short_description1_F">Authentic spaces to experience the famous Azerbaijani tea culture.</string>
    <string name="full_description1_F">
        In Baku, tea is more than a drink—it\'s a ritual. Tucked away in the stone alleys of the Old City, these
        traditional teahouses serve hot black tea in classic armudu (pear-shaped) glasses. It is always
        accompanied by a colorful variety of local jams (like white cherry, walnut, or fig), spiced sweets, and lemon.
    </string>

    <string name="title2_F">National Cuisine Restaurants</string>
    <string name="subtitle2_F">All around the City</string>
    <string name="short_description2_F">Authentic dining spaces serving rich, centuries-old Azerbaijani dishes.</string>
    <string name="full_description2_F">
        To truly experience Baku, one must dive into its culinary heritage. Scattered across the city—from atmospheric
        stone cellars in the Old City to elegant modern venues downtown—these restaurants serve iconic national dishes.
        Here, you can try Shah Plov (royal rice baked in a crispy pastry), tender clay-oven kebabs, and handmade dolma,
        all while surrounded by traditional carpets and live folk music.
    </string>

    <string name="title3_F">Art &amp; Gastro Spaces</string>
    <string name="subtitle3_F">Bayil District / Port Baku</string>
    <string name="short_description3_F">Trendy seaside hubs blending modern art exhibitions with innovative gastro-cafes.</string>
    <string name="full_description3_F">
        Located in beautifully renovated industrial buildings near the sea, these spaces represent Baku\'s modern creative wave.
        Visitors can explore cutting-edge contemporary art galleries and then relax in concept cafés that serve everything
        from fusion Azerbaijani street food to trendy international dishes, all within a vibrant, artistic atmosphere.
    </string>

    <string name="title4_F">Specialty Coffee Shops</string>
    <string name="subtitle4_F">Downtown Baku</string>
    <string name="short_description4_F">The modern face of Baku\'s coffee scene, featuring trendy local roasters.</string>
    <string name="full_description4_F">
        Alongside ancient teahouses, Baku has a booming modern coffee culture. Trendy local spots like Coffee Moffie
        or United Coffee Bros offer high-quality specialty coffee, cozy spaces to work or study, and a vibrant community
        atmosphere for the city\'s youth.
    </string>
</resources>